Torturing Nini
折磨妮妮
Lyrics & Music: Li Zongsheng
詞曲 李宗盛
Mojo mojo mojo spy
Mojo mojo mojo spy
Mojo spy
Mojo spy
This world's a flood of colors bright
這個世界五彩氾濫
Truth and lies confuse our sight
真真假假迷惑我們的眼
Use your heart to see it clear
用你的心认真去看
Find the truth in what you cheer
发现真相就在祝愿
Hey you could or better truth or lies
Hey you could or better 真真假假
Step out from the smoky haze inside
踏步出这心灵的灰烟
Take all your courage, don't be shy
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe you can save the world this time
也许就能拯救这世间
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Please don't forget to like, subscribe, share, and support Mingjing & Diandian's channel
请不吝点赞 订阅 转发 打赏支持明镜与点点栏目
Old Nine hasn't come yet
老九还没来
What should I do
我该怎么办
What to do
怎么办
Go for it
拼了
Stop right there
站住
Who are you
你是谁
You sneaky bastard broke into the vault
你这坏蛋偷偷摸摸潜入保险库
Then you rammed my ice cream with your car
又开车撞翻我的冰激凌
What are you up to?
到底有什么勾当
What ice cream?
什么冰激凌
Still playing dumb, huh?
你还敢装傻
You half-man, half-woman freak
你这半男不女的家伙
You're dead meat!
你受死吧
Courting death!
自寻死路
Locky Qi!
秦乐天
Didn't expect a kid to be so ruthless
没想到小小年纪出手就如此狠毒
Criminal!
罪犯
He must be the one who stole the gem
偷窃宝石的一定是他
No
不是
The culprit will always return to the crime scene
作案者一定会再次回到案发现场的
And you just entered the vault
而且你刚刚进入了保险库
So the criminal must be you
所以罪犯一定是你
Or not
或不是
Say whatever you want
随你怎么说
Hand over the gem now!
快交出宝石来
Sister Lei
雷姐
Please calm down
请你冷静一点
Calm?
冷静
Either way
无论如何
You're the prime suspect now
你现在是最大的嫌疑犯
Please come with us.
请跟我们走一趟吧
You were caught red-handed at the crime scene.
你在犯罪现场被当场抓获
Still trying to talk your way out?
还想狡辩
I was conducting an investigation.
我在进行调查
Investigations are police business.
调查是警察的事
You're just a kid.
你一个小孩子
What are you butting in for?
瞎掺和什么
Many cases are hard to solve on an organizational level.
很多案情都是以组织为基础难以解决的
So I have to step in as an individual.
所以必须要以个人身份介入调查
Captain, I'm sure he's the criminal.
队长 我敢确定他就是罪犯
I suggest you cooperate with us.
我劝你还是跟我们合作的好
After all, this isn't your home turf.
这里毕竟不是你的本城
Detective Huoxing.
霍兴小侦探
Detective.
侦探
The famous young detective of Squid City.
乌贼城大名鼎鼎的少年侦探
At such a young age,
小小年纪便拥有
you possess outstanding detective reasoning talent.
出众的侦探推理天赋
Traveling far and wide,
云游四海
helping police forces everywhere
帮助各地警方
solve many tough cases.
破获多起疑难案件
Never thought I'd run into you here.
没想到会在这儿遇见你
So, little detective, after your personal investigation,
那么小侦探亲临调查
what results did you find?
最终又有什么成果呢
I suspect it's the security guard, Reijie.
我怀疑是保安雷杰
Impressive, impressive.
厉害 厉害
A genius detective indeed lives up to the name.
天才侦探果然不是浪得虚名
Actually, Mr. K, who's handling this exhibition,
其实代理本次展览的Mr.K
also told me in private
也私下跟我说过
that he suspects Reij.
很怀疑雷杰
But what evidence do you have
但你又有什么证据
to say he's the suspect?
说他就是嫌疑犯呢
For now, my evidence isn't very solid,
暂时我的证据也不是很充分
but my first instinct tells me
但是我的第一直觉告诉我
Reiji is very likely the culprit.
雷吉很有可能就是犯人
I'm sure you know, little detective,
想必小侦探也知道
that to catch a suspect,
抓嫌疑犯
you need solid evidence.
必须要有充足的证据吧
Just like how you snuck into the vault
好比你秘密地潜入保险库
and we caught you red-handed.
被我们当场抓获
We have plenty of evidence,
我们拥有了充分的证据
and you've become the prime suspect.
而你就成了最大的嫌疑犯
I was here to investigate.
我是来进行调查的
If you give me enough time,
如果能给我充分的时间
I'll definitely find enough evidence to make an arrest.
我一定会找出足够的证据来捉拿一番
Fine, I trust your skills.
好 我相信你的实力
I'll give you time to find the evidence.
我就给你时间去找证据
Another detective was supposed to assist you,
本来另一位侦探也可以协助你调查
but he suddenly got another assignment,
但他突然接到了其他的任务
so he asked his nephew, Locky Qi, to help you search for clues.
所以就拜托他的侄子齐乐天和你一起寻找线索
I don't need any help.
我不需要任何帮助
Just letting him go like that
就这么放他走了
Uncle's just being lazy himself
老舅明明是自己懒
But he insists on saying
却非说什么
He wants me to sharpen my detective skills
要我锻炼推理能力
And find clues on my own
让我来找线索
Hey, the one who bounced up
跟弹起来的
Treat me to juice today, okay?
请今天喝果汁吧
The meeting spot with Mr. K
跟Mr.K见面的地方
Should be right here, I guess
应该就是这儿吧
Uncle's map is terrible
老舅画的地图真烂
Alright, let's go
好 前进
A little kid like you dares to come to a bar?
小小年纪就敢来酒吧
Where are your parents?
你们家长在哪
I'm Detective Moneybags, how dare you be rude
本侦探钱老婆 你竟敢无礼
My friend
My friend
So it's you, the suspect
原来是你这个嫌疑犯
What are you doing here?
你来这里干嘛
And what are you doing here?
你又在这里干嘛
I'm on a case here
本大爷正在办案
I heard there's a detective fan
我听说有个侦探爱好者
A detective fan is coming to help me with the case
有一个侦探爱好者要来协助我办案
That person is you, right?
那个人就是你吧
Who
谁
Who's a detective fan?
谁是侦探爱好者
Sooner or later, I'll become a world-famous great detective
我早晚会成为威震四海的大侦探
And you?
倒是你
A suspect caught red-handed.
一个被当场抓获的嫌疑犯
Was taken away by the police.
还被警察带走
What's there to be so cocky about?
有什么好嚣张的
Say that again.
请再说一遍
Suspect
嫌疑犯
You wanna fight?
你想打架吗
I bet everyone's thirsty by now.
我想大家都口渴了吧
Let's go to the restaurant across the street and chat over a drink.
不如到对面的restaurant边喝边撩吧
Mr.K
Mr.K
I heard you're also suspicious of this guy, Reg.
听说你也很怀疑雷杰这个人
Hmm-hmm.
嗯哼
Since the vault was stolen,
自从包室丢失之后
I noticed Reijie has become really strange.
我发现雷杰整个人都变得很奇怪
Especially when the police arrived at the scene.
特别是警察赶到现场时
He looks unusually nervous.
他显得异常紧张
And you were caught red-handed at the door of the box storage room.
而且你在包厢库门口被当场抓获时
He even jumped out excitedly to support you.
他还特别兴奋地跳出来支撑你
It's almost like they're trying to frame you.
仿佛很想把罪名栽赃到你身上
I got caught.
我被抓的事情
No need to mention it.
无须再提
At that time, I noticed it.
到时我当时注意到
Sister Lei is also wearing one.
雷姐手上也佩戴着
The same invisibility watch as mine.
和我相同的这款隐身手表
This invisibility watch
这款隐身手表
They were developed by the military for secret agents.
是军方为特工秘密
Infiltrate the enemy's base.
潜入敌方内部
The special tools they developed
而研制出来的特殊工具
Wearing something that can temporarily evade
佩戴着可以暂时躲避
The electronic eye's surveillance footage.
电子眼的监控
Wear this watch
拥有此表
Wanna sneak into the museum.
想潜入博物馆
A piece of cake.
一定轻而易举
Just a broken watch.
光有一块烂表
Does that prove he's guilty?
就能说明他有罪吗
That's Mr. K.
那是Mr.K
You and Reggie both have keys to the vault.
明明你和雷奇两个人都有保险库的钥匙
You both could be suspects in the gem theft.
你俩都有可能是盗窃宝石的嫌疑
No no no no no
No no no no no
This gem is a national treasure of our country.
这块宝石乃是我国的珍宝
The treasures abroad are basically my treasures.
出国的珍宝就等于是我的珍宝
Why would I steal something I already own?
我又怎么会偷输于自己的东西呢
And if we don't get the gem back...
而且不找回宝石
I... I can't go back now.
我 我就没脸回去了
On the night of the crime, what were you all doing?
案发当晚 你们都做了些什么
That night
那天晚上
We first met at the shop across the street.
我们先是一起在对面那家
A manly man drinks at the bar.
大男子酒吧喝酒
I'm not good with alcohol.
我不胜酒理
But Sister Lei kept pushing drinks on me in a really shady way.
可雷姐却一直特别阴气地劝酒
Later, Sister Lei said I drank too much.
后来雷姐说我喝多了
I'll go along with that and head to her apartment.
就附和到她的公寓消息
I remember walking through the apartment entrance.
我记得一进公寓大门
Got caught by the shadow guard at the gate.
就被扣影挂影的门卫
Chew him out.
臭骂一顿
I asked Sister Lei why she got yelled at.
我问雷姐为什么会被骂
She said the door to her apartment was just a little damp.
她说她住的公寓门就是湿一点
We're back too late.
我们回来太晚了
The guard is troubled.
门卫很困扰
Then as soon as I got to his place, I couldn't stop tripping.
然后我一到他的家里就凹凸不止
He said he'd go find me some hangover cure.
他说去帮我找接酒药
Let me rest in bed first.
让我先到床上休息
The moment I hit the bed, I was out like a light.
我一躺上床就昏昏沉沉地睡着了
No idea how long it's been.
也不知道过了多久
I was woken up by Sister Lei.
我被蕾姐叫醒
She called for the antidote.
她招来了接酒药
I feel super energetic after eating this.
我吃完变得特别精神
Then the two of us watched it together.
然后我们两个就一起看
11:30 PM live TV broadcast
23点30分电视直播的
Tiny Clash Show
微小对对碰节目
The show is pretty fun.
节目很有趣
After watching that show
看完那个节目
We just talked until dawn.
我们就一起聊到天亮
So that's how it is.
这么说
The time of the crime.
案发的时间
He should be with you
他应该和你在一起
Watching TV, right?
看电视才对哦
It's too early to jump to conclusions.
现在断言还太早
Let's go check out Reggie's apartment together.
我们一起到雷杰公寓看看
That doesn't fit at all.
特别不像
A person all alone and lonely.
一个人孤单寂寞
Life at that moment—
当时人生
It's bound to have some unhappiness.
难免会有些不快乐
Saying goodbye to today
告别今天
Always makes you feel lost.
总是让人觉得失落
Look at tomorrow,
看看明天
Waving to each other on the horizon.
在地平线相互招手
Every day goes by with sunrise and sunset,
每天就在日升日落
Turning into time, dreaming more.
转进时间幻想更多
Looking forward to every second, every moment of life.
期待生命中每一秒每一刻
My bright eyes are sparkling.
我明亮的眼睛在闪烁
A smile that greets the sunlight,
迎着阳光的笑容
Stepping through the screaming crossroads.
踏破桥桥中在尖叫的路口
I, Inspector Sima, even if it costs me my apprentice,
我司马刚就算干脑徒弟
Will bring the bad guys to justice.
也要把坏人绳之一髮
Falling into your hands is my bad luck,
栽在你们手上算我倒霉
But I was just following orders.
但我是被人指使的
He used me and then sold me out.
他达成目的后就出卖了我
The mastermind behind all this—
这整个幕后黑手教师
Is it the Eye of Light?
是光明之眼吗